{
    "id": "a95cfbe209114bd482d530c09c4b4495",
    "title": "Reported Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He asked me what ……………………….. doing there.",
            "description": "In reported questions the subject goes before the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "was I",
                "I was"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he ………………………….. his examination.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the reported speech will also be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "has passed",
                "had passed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he ……………………… unwell.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the reported speech will also be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy said that he ………………………… then.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the reported speech will also be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "slept",
                "was sleeping",
                "is sleeping"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The stranger asked where ……………………",
            "description": "Do is not used in reported questions.",
            "answers": [
                "l live",
                "I lived",
                "did I live"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctor said that the patient ……………………… in the night.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the reported speech will also be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "has died",
                "had died"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The girl exclaimed that she …………………….. very clever.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "is",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I wrote that I ………………………… him next day.",
            "description": "Would is the past tense of will in direct speech. When we convert this into direct speech, we get: He wrote, ‘I will visit you tomorrow.’",
            "answers": [
                "visited",
                "will visit",
                "would visit"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me …………………………. I knew his name.",
            "description": "We use if or whether to report questions.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "whether",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked the girl if she ……………………… me her pen.",
            "description": "I asked the girl, 'Will you lend me your pen?' When we convert this into indirect speech we get: I asked the girl whether she would lend me her pen. ",
            "answers": [
                "will lend",
                "would lend",
                "lent"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He told us that he ………………………. for an hour.",
            "description": "He told us, 'I have waited for an hour.' When we convert this into indirect speech we get: He told us that he had waited for an hour. ",
            "answers": [
                "has waited",
                "had waited"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The speaker said that it …………………… him great pleasure to be there that evening.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the reported speech will also be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "gives",
                "has given",
                "gave"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}